all right
[Music]
in the United States the number one risk
factor for death is the American diet
associated with more deaths than any
other risk factor responsible for like
half a million mothers fathers sisters
brothers friends and family dying every
year because of what they ate mostly
from cardiovascular disease that's where
plant-based diets can come in associated
with low risk of developing
cardiovascular disease lower risk of
dying from cardiovascular disease and in
fact the low risk of dying from all
causes put together
progressively increasing the intake of
plant Foods by reducing the amount of
intake of animal Foods may enable us to
live longer healthier lives and it
doesn't take much if you look at the
largest cohort study on diet and healthy
in history the nihaarp study they found
that replacing just three percent of
energy from animal protein with plant
protein was associated with a 10 lower
overall mortality in both men and women
of all the animal protein sources eggs
were the worst swapping in three percent
plant protein for egg protein was
associated with twice the benefit
exceeding 20 percent lower mortality in
men and women
the researchers concluded that the study
provides evidence for public health
recommendations regarding dietary
modifications in terms of choice of
protein sources that may promote Health
and Longevity and plant protein is
preferable now healthy plant-based diets
are associated with a low risk of all
cost mortality but with an emphasis on
healthy when individuals increase their
consumption of plant Foods while
decreasing their intake of animal Foods
there could be an increase in their
consumption of less healthy options
highly processed plant foods like Coke
and Wonder Bread one cannot assume that
simply avoiding animal foods will
necessarily produce such a healthy diet
in order to distinguish between
healthful and unhelpful vegan diets the
term Whole Food plant-based diet is
attributed to Cornell professor emeritus
and nutritional biochemistry Dr T Colin
Campbell if you look at India for
example you see a decreasing in whole
plant food content of their diets along
with an increasing risk of obesity and
non-communicable chronic diseases this
may help explain why disease rates are
on the rise even in a country with a
large vegetarian contingent this may
help explain why health-wise vegans in
the U.S do better than vegans in the UK
the number one reason people in the U.S
eat plant-based is health and so they
eat more plants more fiber vitamin C
only found concentrated in whole plant
Foods whereas the number one reason
given in the UK is Animal Welfare
reasons and so they may be more likely
to just switch over to vegan Donuts you
can't know if vegans really have to eat
more plants though until you put it to
the test an evaluation of an eight-week
Whole Food plant-based lifestyle
modification program in which two dozen
were already eating vegetarian or vegan
but not necessarily Whole Food
plant-based and after eight weeks even
those who already started out vegetarian
or vegan experienced significant weight
loss and reductions in cholesterol they
lost 10 pounds and dropped their LDL
cholesterol 15 points so even a
short-term Whole Food plant-based
dietary intervention May provide
significant benefits for non-vegetarians
vegetarians and vegans alike we have a
food supply in which junk is a food
group willfully engineered to maximize
eating for profit and the industry will
happily make all the vegan junk we're
willing to buy in fact if you compare
the consumption of ultra processed junk
across different eating patterns
vegetarians and vegans without going to
be eating the most junk like potato
chips and cookies
not all plant-based Foods exert the same
health effects
but what about animal food these
researchers separately scored the
quality of different plant-based foods
with a plant-based diet Quality Index
and also various animal Foods in an
animal-based diet quality index for
example if you consider processed meats
and red meats as unhealthy animal foods
but Fish seafood Dairy and poultry as
healthy animal foods and you throw eggs
in with the unhealthy too based on the
most recent evidence they found that the
higher quality of plant Foods the longer
you live the lower all-cause mortality
but no independent Association was found
for the quality of animal Foods meaning
they all seemed just as bad in terms of
cancer mortality heart disease mortality
and all-cause mortality
in light of the expanding Global threat
of cardiovascular disease large-scale
shifts towards healthy plant-based diets
are imperative to ensure future human
health but all plant foods are not
created equal
[Music]
foreign